ROHITYADAV

SOCIAL MEDIA & MARKETING MANAGER

Mumbai +91 8454954654 rohity750@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

A marketing enthusiast with experience of over 7 years in scaling businesses digitally and now seeking a challenging and rewarding opportunity in an organization that recognizes, utilizes, and nurtures my ideation, creative, analytical and technical skills

WORK EXPERIENCE

Social Media Lead Burns & McDonnell India

Feb 2023 - Present

Demonstrated exceptional leadership by overseeing digital outreach plans, resulting in a phenomenal growth rate of the brand's social presence by increasing organic followers by 45,000+, 100K visitors, and increasing engagement by 200% in the span of 1.6 years.

- Communications: Leading and managing strategies, providing training to ensure consistent and effective messaging across various channels.
- Social Media Management: Planning, developing, and executing social media campaigns, enhancing brand visibility and engagement on platforms including Linkedln, My Company, and Facebook.
- Video Ideation: Oversee the ideation, production, and distribution of video content to support
 marketing campaigns, ensuring alignment with brand guidelines and communication
 objectives.
- Content Strategy: Developing and implementing comprehensive content strategies to increase audience engagement and drive brand awareness.
- Analytics and Reporting: Monitoring social media metrics and performance to optimize future campaigns and strategies.
- Team Leadership: Coordinating with cross-functional teams, including internal
 communications, HR, and engineering departments, to ensure cohesive communication efforts
 and successful project execution. Upskilled leadership training and certified by Leading
 with Pride.
- Crisis Management: Managing and responding to potential social media crises, maintaining a
 positive brand image, and mitigating risks.
- Paid Media: Running LinkedIn, Instagram, and Facebook Ads to create brand awareness, website visits, and generate leads.
- DEI Advocacy: Suggested and executed DEI initiatives to spread awareness and sensitize
 employees about issues such as LGBTQ+, PwD, gender biases, and age biases. Organized
 events such as Diversity Fair, sensitization sessions with Team Vision (NGO for blind and
 partially blind individuals) and a talk show with mothers of queer children to spread awareness
 about LGBTQ+ and PwD communities.

Tools & Software Used: HubSpot, LinkedIn Ads, LinkedIn My Company, Meta Ads.

Successfully executed organic and paid social media strategies on Instagram, Facebook and LinkedIn to **generate over 50,000 leads** of students aspiring to study abroad.

- **Social Media Management:** Planning social media calendar and making strategies for successful execution to generate leads and queries related to studying abroad.
- Influencer Marketing: Creating a database of influencers, reaching out to them and negotiating deals with them. Make strategies to successfully execute influencer collaborations on social media, blogs or campus.
- Analytics & Metrics: Weekly and monthly report creation to track the performance of content and create a plan of action for further successful execution.
- Reel Creation: Scripting, storyboarding, editing and publishing reels. Collaborating with different teams to execute the same.
- Online Reputation Management: Social listening to monitor the queries and responses received through comments and messages. Maintaining a healthy brand messaging on social platforms.
- Paid Media: Strategize and execute Instagram and Facebook ads. Defining audience, demographics and budget to achieve the desired results, such as student inquiries for studying abroad.

Tools & Software Used: HubSpot, Canva, VN Editor, Meta Ads.

Programming Head & Social Media Strategiest BhaDiPa (Vishay Khol & Bha2Pa)

Jun 2021 - Nov 2021

- Planning, executing and strategizing execution on both brand channels' YouTube, Instagram and Facebook.
- Creating a database of influencers and collaborators and conceptualizing a shoot with them.
- Coordinating with designated teams to execute campaigns, strategies, shoots, and execution
 of the final content.
- Planning and tracking the progress of the shooting process, such as concept creation, shortlisting talents, and collaborating with teams to plan and execute shoots, video edits, approval and final execution on social media.
- Client coordination for brainstorming, discussing, closing deals and final approvals.

Assistant Social Media Manager Edgytal Digital Solutions

Jan 2020 - Apr 2021

- Managing the organic and paid social media executions of 5 clients and company profile at once.
- Creating content calendars, campaigns and strategies for existing and potential new clients.
- generating weekly and monthly reports to track the success of the campaign and content.
- Managing and monitoring Facebook Ads, LinkedIn Ads, and Instagram Ads for brand awareness, website visits and generating leads.
- Assisting in influencer activity & events for campaign promotions.

Social Media Executive Aug 2018 - Dec 2019

Ultra Media & Entertainment pvt. ltd.

- Managing the social media activities of 4 brand channels.
- Creating strategies to repurpose content across various social media platforms for a better reach. Designing flyers and editing videos.
- Making videos eligible for Facebook Monetization through Watch Party, repurposing, etc.
- Using meme marketing to promote existing content like movies, songs, serials, and short scenes.
- Scripting and assisting in shoots for the Food Channel.
- Helped translate videos into regional languages for better reach. (e.g., translation of recipe videos into Hindi and Marathi language).
- Creating pitch documents for client collaborations.

Social Media & Influencer Management Executive

Jun 2017 - Aug 2018

Kmedia Digital Agency

- Managing social media planning and execution of 4-5 clients.
- Responding to online queries, feedback, reviews, and comments across social media platforms.
- Creating a database of food and lifestyle influencers, reaching out to them for barter collaborations and tracking the deliverables.
- Client coordination, presentation and report analysis on daily, weekly and monthly basis.

EDUCATION

Leadership Certification

2024

Leading with Pride

Digital Marketing Certification

2018

The Digital Brunch

BSc(IT) - Passed with 'O' grade

2014-2017

K. C. College of Arts, Commerce & Science,

Churchgate

HSC - passed with 78.31%

2012-2014

D. G. Ruparel College of Arts, Commerce & Science,

Matunga Rd, Mumbai

SSC - passed with 87.45%

2012

St. Ignatius High School, Mahalaxmi, Mumbai

SOCIAL MEDIA

PERSONAL DETAILS

Instagram: www.instagram.com/yadavjiblogs DOB: 28-03-1996

Location: Mumbai, India

Gender: Male

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/loverohityadav Pronouns: He/Him/His